{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Where the Wild Things Are","incorrectAnswers":["The Cat in the Hat","Green Eggs and Ham","Goodnight Moon"],"question":"What 2009 film is based on Maurice Sendak's beloved children's classic?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Uriah Heep"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Love Me Do'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Ziggurat","incorrectAnswers":["Pyramid","Obelisk","Sphinx"],"question":"What is the name of the stepped structure used as a temple by Mesopotamian cultures?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Vladimir Nabokov","incorrectAnswers":["Ayn Rand","Kurt Vonnegut","Mikhail Bulgakov"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Lolita (2010 Penguin Classics ed.)'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rihanna","incorrectAnswers":["Drake","Nicki Minaj","Ricky Martin"],"question":"Which singer released the studio album 'Rated R'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Nile Rodgers","incorrectAnswers":["Quincy Jones","Phil Spector","George Martin"],"question":"Who produced David Bowie's 1983 album \"Let's Dance\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Nine Stories","incorrectAnswers":["The Metamorphosis","Blood Meridian","Portnoy's Complaint"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Seymour Glass'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Wait for It\" - Hamilton","incorrectAnswers":["\"Defying Gravity\" - Wicked","\"Edelweiss\" - The Sound of Music","\"I Dreamed a Dream\" - Les Misérables"],"question":"Which song from a musical begins with the lyrics: \"Theodosia writes me a letter every day...\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Baseball","incorrectAnswers":["Dodgeball","Fistball","Tetherball"],"question":"The sport named softball is a direct descendant of which other sport?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"7 Swans A Swimming","incorrectAnswers":["7 Maids a Milking","7 Lords A Leaping","7 Drummers Drumming"],"question":"What did 'my true love give to me' on the seventh day of Christmas?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Taxi Drivers","incorrectAnswers":["Beefeaters","Lawyers","The Mayor"],"question":"Who needs to pass an exam called \"The Knowledge\" to do their job in London?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Fettuccine","incorrectAnswers":["Orecchiette","Lasagne","Cavatappi"],"question":"Which pasta's name means 'Little ribbons'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Gillettes","incorrectAnswers":["Remingtons","Wahls","Brauns"],"question":"What unit was used to measure the strength of early lasers?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Poi","incorrectAnswers":["Lomi-lomi","Huli-huli","Kalua"],"question":"What traditional Hawaiian dish is made by pounding cooked taro root into a paste and is traditionally eaten with fingers?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A hormone","incorrectAnswers":["A gland","An amino acid","A sugar"],"question":"What is testosterone?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Apple","incorrectAnswers":["Mango","Papaya","Pineapple"],"question":"Which of these fruits is not a tropical fruit?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Propellers","incorrectAnswers":["Fans","Turbines","Spinnies"],"question":"What are the rotating blades on an aircraft called?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Darth Vader","incorrectAnswers":["Obi-Wan Kenobi","Han Solo","Yoda"],"question":"In Star Wars, who is Luke Skywalker's father?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ahmadi","incorrectAnswers":["Sunni","Shia","Sufi"],"question":"Which of the following is not a main branch of Islam?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Simon & Garfunkel","incorrectAnswers":["Hall & Oates","Ike & Tina Turner","The Everley Brothers"],"question":"Which Pair Had The Best Selling Album In Both 1970 And 1971?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Radiohead","incorrectAnswers":["Goldfrapp","U2","Coldplay"],"question":"Thom Yorke is the lead singer of which alternative rock band?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Christopher Lee","incorrectAnswers":["Patrick Stewart","Ian McKellen","Anthony Hopkins"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Saruman in The Lord of the Rings?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Matthew McConaughey","incorrectAnswers":["Ryan Reynolds","Jim Carrey","Hugh Jackman"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including Interstellar and Dallas Buyers Club?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"One Direction","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Orchestral Manoeuvres in the Dark","Blur"],"question":"Which English-Irish boy band released the studio album 'Take Me Home'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Picture postcards","incorrectAnswers":["The structure of diseased tissues","Changes in social norms","Ethics"],"question":"What is deltiology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"University of Oxford","incorrectAnswers":["University of Cambridge","University of Edinburgh","University of London"],"question":"Which is the oldest university in the UK?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Killing Me Softly","incorrectAnswers":["The Man Who Sold the World","Smells Like Teen Spirit","You Really Got Me"],"question":"Which song, originally recorded by Roberta Flack, was later covered by The Fugees?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A flight","incorrectAnswers":["A run","A sounder","A muster"],"question":"What is the word for a group of doves?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mali","incorrectAnswers":["Burkina Faso","Mauritania","Ivory Coast"],"question":"The City Of Timbuktu Is In Which African Country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hinduism","incorrectAnswers":["Buddhism","Islam","Christianity"],"question":"Which religion celebrates the festivals of Diwali and Holi?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Strawberry","incorrectAnswers":["Nectarine","Peach","Cherry"],"question":"Which of these fruits does not contain a stone?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Opel","incorrectAnswers":["Honda","Ford","Rolls-Royce"],"question":"The Corsa is a model of car made by which manufacturer?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Apples","incorrectAnswers":["Bananas","Cherries","Carrots"],"question":"What Would You Traditionally 'Bob' For At Halloween?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Gobbledygook","incorrectAnswers":["Gerbunctious","Lackadaisical","Hocus"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'language that is meaningless'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Eggnog","incorrectAnswers":["Hot chocolate","Mulled wine","Cider"],"question":"What is the name of the cool, creamy Christmas drink that is generally consumed during the holidays?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"4","incorrectAnswers":["2","6","8"],"question":"How Many 75cl Bottles Of Champagne Would You Get From A Jeroboam?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Vinson","incorrectAnswers":["Aconcagua","Everest","Denali"],"question":"What is the highest peak on Antarctica?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Beyoncé","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Drake","Nicki Minaj"],"question":"Who played the role of Nala in the 2019 remake of The Lion King?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Cabotage","incorrectAnswers":["Halfpace","Dragoman","Bumfuzzle"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'coastal navigation; the exclusive right of a country to control the air traffic within its borders'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Percussion","incorrectAnswers":["String","Wind","Keyboard"],"question":"What type of instrument is a xylophone?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hephaistos","incorrectAnswers":["Apollo","Mars","Ares"],"question":"Who is the Greek equivalent of the Roman god Vulcan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Cheshire Cat's","incorrectAnswers":["Albert Einstein's","Imhotep's","Rita Skeeter's"],"question":"Whose smile remained after the rest of it had vanished?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Release the Kraken!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"With great power comes great responsiblity.\"","\"Rosebud.\"","\"You can't handle the truth!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Clash of the Titans'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Stuttgart","incorrectAnswers":["Hamburg","Munich","Berlin"],"question":"What German city was named for a stud farm that was formerly on the site?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"John Travolta","incorrectAnswers":["Joe Pesci","Malcolm McDowell","Errol Flynn"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Tony Manero in Saturday Night Fever?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Hilary Duff","incorrectAnswers":["Olivia Wilde","Madonna","Sophia Loren"],"question":"Which actress has played roles in both Gossip Girl and Ghost Whisperer?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Netherlands ","incorrectAnswers":["Thailand","Lesotho","Bangladesh"],"question":"Which Country has a name that literally means 'lower lands'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Churchill Downs","incorrectAnswers":["Pimlico Race Course","Belmont Park","Saratoga Race Course"],"question":"Which site hosts the famous horse racing event known as the Kentucky Derby?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Nine","incorrectAnswers":["Seven","Six","Eight"],"question":"How many planets are there in our solar system?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Denis Diderot","incorrectAnswers":["Spinoza","Ludwig Wittgenstein","Friedrich Nietzsche"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Man will never be free until the last king is strangled with the entrails of the last priest'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Secretariat","incorrectAnswers":["Man o' War","Sea Biscuit","Affirmed"],"question":"What was the name of the horse that won the Belmont in 1973 by a record 31 lengths?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sabrina, Kelly, Jill","incorrectAnswers":["Ashley, Michelle, Tina","Joan, Lucy, Emily","Mary, Louise, Jackie"],"question":"What were the character names of the 3 lead women of Charlie's Angels?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Fantastic Four","incorrectAnswers":["The X-Men","The Avengers","The Justice League"],"question":"Which famous group includes the characters Reed Richards, Sue Richards, The Human Torch, and The Thing?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Delaware","incorrectAnswers":["Wilmington","Maryland","Pennsylvania"],"question":"Which river did George Washington famously cross in the American Revolutionary War?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Direct Message","incorrectAnswers":["Double Meaning","Do Me","Dire Mood"],"question":"If someone typed the letters 'DM' in a message, what would they mean?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"10 Lords A Leaping","incorrectAnswers":["10 Pipers Piping","10 Maids A Milking","10 Drummers Drumming"],"question":"What did 'my true love give to me' on the tenth day of Christmas?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Linkin Park","incorrectAnswers":["Alice in Chains","Hollywood Undead","System of a Down"],"question":"Which American rock band released the studio album 'Hybrid Theory'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Yemen","incorrectAnswers":["France","Australia","Turkey"],"question":"In which country would you find the Socotra Archipelago?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Loudness","incorrectAnswers":["Light","Radiation","Electrical Resistance"],"question":"A Phon is a unit of what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Singapore","incorrectAnswers":["Mauritius","United States","North Africa"],"question":"Where in the world would you most expect to be served Chilli Crab?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Apartment","incorrectAnswers":["The Alamo","Elmer Gantry","Sons and Lovers"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1960?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Victoria Falls","incorrectAnswers":["The Iguazu Falls","The Niagara Falls","The Angel Falls"],"question":"Which waterfall is on the Zambezi River, on the border between Zambia and Zimbabwe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Telemachus","incorrectAnswers":["Perseus","Archimedes","Icarus"],"question":"Who was Odysseus' son, who grew to manhood in his absence?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Truman Show","incorrectAnswers":["Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade","The Matrix","The Batman"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'An insurance salesman discovers his whole life is actually a reality TV show.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"January 6th","incorrectAnswers":["June 20th","December 1st","October 19th"],"question":"Which date on the Christian calendar marks The Epiphany, when Jesus, Mary and Joseph met The Three Wise Men?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Socrates","incorrectAnswers":["Spinoza","Ludwig Wittgenstein","Karl Marx"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'The unexamined life is not worth living'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Nicki Minaj","incorrectAnswers":["Hikaru Utada","Alanis Morissette","Ludacris"],"question":"Which singer released the song 'Bitch I'm Madonna'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Jerusalem","incorrectAnswers":["Alexandria","Istanbul","Rome"],"question":"Godfrey of Bouillon was a leader of the First Crusade and was elected ruler of what city after its capture?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Stockholm","incorrectAnswers":["Madrid","Moscow","Athens"],"question":"What is the name of the city that is home to both the Nobel Museum and ABBA The Museum?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Radiohead","incorrectAnswers":["Goldfrapp","Cream","Girls Aloud"],"question":"Which English rock band released the studio album 'OK Computer'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"French","incorrectAnswers":["Canadian","Swiss","Belgian"],"question":"What was the nationality of the mathematician Joseph Fourier?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Louis Bleriot","incorrectAnswers":["Jacques Peralle","Martin Robertson","Arnold Clark"],"question":"Who, in 1909, became the first man to fly across the English Channel?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Canelé","incorrectAnswers":["Strudel","Kringle","Cannoli"],"question":"Which of these is a small French pastry flavored with rum and vanilla with a soft and tender custard center and a dark, thick caramelized crust?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Intermittent","incorrectAnswers":["Continuous","Spontaneous","Frequent"],"question":"What word describes starting and stopping at intervals?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Game Boy","incorrectAnswers":["Atari 2600","Sega Genesis","PlayStation"],"question":"Which popular games console was released by Nintendo in 1998?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"the Jehovah's Witnesses","incorrectAnswers":["the Mormons","the Catholics","the Methodists"],"question":"What is the name of the religious group with the print magazine \"The Watchtower\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Nine","incorrectAnswers":["Three","None","One"],"question":"How Many Children Did Queen Victoria Have?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Germany","incorrectAnswers":["Croatia","San Marino","Bosnia and Herzegovina"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Austria?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Freeway Of Love","incorrectAnswers":["The Freedom Freeway","Freeway Five","The Respect Freeway"],"question":"Which Freeway Did \"Aretha Franklin\" Sing About?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Parasite","incorrectAnswers":["Ford v Ferrari","The Irishman","Jojo Rabbit"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2019?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Salzburg","incorrectAnswers":["Lisbon","Brussels","Athens"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Austria?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Nelson Mandela","incorrectAnswers":["Kgalema Motlanthe","F.W. de Klerk","Thabo Mbeki"],"question":"Who was the first president of South Africa?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Live in your world. Play in ours.","incorrectAnswers":["Connecting people","The future is exciting. Ready?","Ideas for Life"],"question":"What is the marketing slogan of PlayStation?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["Norway","Guatemala","Portugal"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of Cinque Terre?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hexagon","incorrectAnswers":["Pentagon","Octagon","Dodecahedron"],"question":"What is the mathematical term used to describe the shape of a cell in a honeycomb? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"David Bowie","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Madonna","Mika"],"question":"Which musician released the album 'Aladdin Sane'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Don't Leave Me This Way","incorrectAnswers":["Ice Ice Baby","In-A-Gadda-Da-Vida","Rebirth of Slick (Cool Like Dat)"],"question":"What song did Thelma Houston have a hit with in 1976?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Montreal ","incorrectAnswers":["Sao Paolo","Los Angeles","London"],"question":"What major city is on an island in the St Lawrence River?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"6","incorrectAnswers":["3","10","8"],"question":"How Many Players Are There In A Volleyball Team?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beach Boys","incorrectAnswers":["Swans","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American rock band released the studio album 'Smiley Smile'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Blues","incorrectAnswers":["The Hoops","The Citizens","Cottagers"],"question":"What is the nickname of the English football team Birmingham City?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A run","incorrectAnswers":["A stud","A parliament","A exaltation"],"question":"What is the word for a group of poultry?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Donkey","incorrectAnswers":["Sheep","Goat","Horse"],"question":"Of What Is A Jenny The Female?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"In Real Life","incorrectAnswers":["I Remember Losing","Idiots Receive Laughter","I Really Love"],"question":"What do people mean when type the letters 'IRL' in a message on the internet?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Alexandre Dumas","incorrectAnswers":["Anatole France","Gustave Flaubert","Charles Perrault"],"question":"Which author wrote 'D'Artagnan Romances'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Henry Kissinger","incorrectAnswers":["John Quincy Adams","Condoleezza Rice","Robert Gates"],"question":"Which U.S. Secretary of State won the Nobel Peace Prize in 1973?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Finger lickin' good","incorrectAnswers":["I'm loving it","Seafood Differently","This is not just food..."],"question":"Which marketing slogan would you associate with KFC?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Radiohead","incorrectAnswers":["Goldfrapp","Cream","Girls Aloud"],"question":"Which English rock band released the album 'In Rainbows'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Borg","incorrectAnswers":["The Klingons","The Romulans","The Dominion"],"question":"Which deadly enemy race in \"Star Trek\" were known for their catchphrase: \"Resistance is futile\"?","difficulty":"hard"},